A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Overseas Office, Asia, Hanoi Field Office, Office Files of Charles R. Bailey FA672
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Overseas Office, Asia, Hanoi Field Office, Office Files of Charles R. Bailey
1999-2007
Rockefeller Archive Center
Bailey, Charles R. (Charles Randall) (1938)
Ford Foundation
FA672
1.69 Cubic Feet 1 record storage box and 1 letter document box
Arrangement
Arranged in 2 series by file type.
Collection arrangement is as follows:
Series I. Correspondence Files, 2001-2007
Series II. Subject Files, 1999-2006
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
Primarily contains correspondence and subject files.
Biographical / Historical
Charles Bailey is a public policy specialist who held various positions at the Ford Foundation.
Bailey joined the Ford Foundation in 1972 as an Assistant Program Officer and an Assistant Representative for India, Nepal, and Sri Lanka. He stayed in that position until 1976 when he left the Foundation to earn his Ph.D. in natural resource economics from Cornell University. After completing his education, he returned to the Ford Foundation as an Assistant Program Officer and an Assistant Representative for the Middle East and North Africa Program in 1982. He was based in the Khartoum, Sudan office for this position. Then in 1985, he became the Foundation's Representative for Bangladesh. He returned to Africa in 1990 and served as the Foundation's Representative for Eastern and Southern Africa until an organizational change when the Foundation split out its programming for the Eastern Africa and Southern Africa regions. In 1996, he served as the Foundation's Representative for Eastern Africa and was based in the Nairobi, Kenya office. He moved to the Hanoi, Vietnam office in 1997 to work as the Foundation's Representative for Vietnam and Thailand and remained in that position until 2007. Bailey's last position at the Foundation was as Director for the Special Initiative on Agent Orange/Dioxin. Bailey and the project moved to the Aspen Institute in 2011.
Bailey continued as Director for the Agent Orange in Vietnam Program at Aspen until 2014. In addition to a Ph.D. from Cornell, Bailey earned a B.A. in history and political science from Swarthmore College in 1967 and a M.P.A. in modernization and economic development from Princeton University in 1972.
- Correspondence Files, 2001-2007; I; 1.31 Cubic Feet 1 record storage box
  - 2001 Chronological Correspondence, 2001 September-December (Box 1)
  - 2002 Chronological Correspondence, 2002 January-September (Box 1)
  - 2002-2003 Chronological Correspondence, 2002 September-2003 July (Box 1)
  - 2003-2004 Chronological Correspondence, 2003 September-2004 September (Box 1)
  - 2004-2006 Chronological Correspondence, 2004 October-2006 April (Box 1)
  - 2006-2007 Chronological Correspondence, 2006 March-2007 September (Box 1)
- Subject Files, 1999-2006; II; 0.38 Cubic Feet
  - Ford Foundation Permit Renewal -- Working File (folder 1), 1999 (Box 2)
  - Ford Foundation Permit Renewal -- Working File (folder 2), 1999 (Box 2)
  - Vietnamese Personal Income Tax Regulations (folder 1), 2004-2006 (Box 2)
  - Vietnamese Personal Income Tax Regulations (folder 2), 2005-2006 (Box 2)